Mohit Ramwani

Software Engineer at Microsoft

Summary

"The craving to learn new things should never end" - this is what I believe in.

I had been introduced to the "World of Computers" during grade 4 at my school & since then, the domain of Computer Science has captured my interest. I opted for IT, as my elective, at high school, helping me gain an insight into JavaScript and HTML. I chose Computer Engineering as my major in my undergrad which not only gave me an introduction to various programming languages such as C, C++, Java, C# but also helped me to gain practical experience by working on labs & related projects. I also participated in quiz competitions, paper presentations, project competitions etc. where my knowledge in the domain was put to test. We, in a group of 4, developed an Android app, sponsored by Persistent Systems Ltd, Pune, India, as a final year undergrad project.

I am currently pursuing MS in Computer Science at Syracuse University. I got an opportunity to work as a Software Engineer Intern at SAVVIS, a CenturyLink Company in Summer 2013. Our team developed a Web Service Catalog, which was developed to manage tech debt by making use of Neo4j, HTML, promises in JavaScript, CSS & a bit of Python SUDS.

I also worked as Software Developer Intern at C Speed, LLC in Fall 2013 & made a significant contribution in developing TweakUI application for General Electric's Thor device. The application was built on Microsoft .NET platform and used MVVM design pattern. It helped me improve my software developing as well as testing skills and gave me hands on experience to work on entire software development life cycle.

I worked on a couple of projects in Microsoft where I was working as SDET Intern in Summer 2014. Both of them were challenging and I worked on the entire SDLC. It was a fantastic experience which involved working on SQL Server Management Studio, SQL Server Report Builder, Build Workflow activities in Visual Studio 2013 & testing and compliance tools. I successfully completed both my projects.

Experience

Software Engineer at Microsoft

February 2015 - Present

Mentor at Microsoft

June 2016 - September 2016 (4 months)

- Got a great opportunity this Summer (2016) to mentor an Explorer Intern in our team Michael Araya, pursuing Computer Science at Stanford University.
- Spent time with him to understand what his interests were and which area would he like to explore and contribute
- Assigned him projects and tasks to work on, while continuously helping him get comfortable with the technologies
- Had great discussions with him on what his take was on projects, services owned by the team and what changes/features could make it better

Software Development Engineer in Test (SDET) Intern at Microsoft

May 2014 - August 2014 (4 months)

My responsibilities include:

- 1. Understand the structure of the existing data pipeline and monitor its health.
- 2. Solve the issues in the dashboard
- 3. Improve the efficiency of the data pipeline by making use of efficient SQL queries
- 4. Build an automated workflow which makes use of the testing and compliance tools

Software Developer Intern at C Speed

August 2013 - December 2013 (5 months)

Developed TweakUI application on Microsoft .NET platform, utilizing WPF, using Model View View-Model design pattern. It helps for efficient communication with the General Electric's Thor device, which consists of a handset and a probe. Different parameters such as brightness, sharpness etc. can be viewed and modified by using the application.

Software Engineer Intern at Savvis

May 2013 - August 2013 (4 months)

- -Management of tech debt by developing Web Service Catalog, an excellent robust tool which provides the users to get details of services, components and databases in a tabular as well as graphical format and modify them, depending on user access rights.
- -The catalog makes use of Neo4j, HTML, Javascript, CSS, Promises in Javascript, Python SUDS.
- -Worked on Disaster Recovery

Project Intern at Persistent Systems

August 2011 - March 2012 (8 months)

Developed an Android application- "Event based Profile Manager for SmartPhones". A user friendly and easy to use application which manages the profiles on the smartphones based on four triggers- manual, agenda, meeting and location. Presented a paper on it in "International Conference on Current Trends and Challenges in Management, Engineering, Computer Application and Technology (ICCTCMECAT 2012)".

Education

Syracuse University

Master of Science (MS), Computer Science, 2012 - 2014

University of Pune

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer Engineering, 2008 - 2012

HPT Arts & RYK Science College

2006 - 2008

St. Philomena's Convent High School

1994 - 2006

Honors and Awards

Letter of Appreciation for being College Topper, Best Outgoing Student in Primary Section, Best Project in Project Competition- Promanifesto, Among the Top 1% of students in 6th National Level I.T. Aptitude Test conducted by NIIT

Mohit Ramwani

Software Engineer at Microsoft



Contact Mohit on LinkedIn